Keep going!
I'll help you ants out.
There!
See ya later!
Ouch!
The Day of Nobita's Birth
Today's a great day!
Hey, Doraemon!
Oh, welcome home.
What is Mum doing today?
She's very busy with cleaning and shopping.
Shopping?
Hmm?
Since it's summer vacation, why don't you help your mum by running errands?
Not really, because....
Oh, today's August 7.
Right, your birthday!
Nobita!
Coming!
Happiness is calling me!
I hear the footprints of my birthday gift.
Nobita!
Yes?
Care to explain what's this?
Well....
How many times do I have to remind you to "take the swim pants out of bag when dry"?
Thought I'd do it later.
Do it instantly otherwise it's same as not doing it.
What about your homework? Did you finished it?
I will do it later.
Seriously... ... You always say that...
You're the same as ever.
You suffer like this always.
But because today's....
Today's nothing special!
Do this instant, young man!
I WILL do it! Happy now?
What is with your tone?
But you always tell me to work hard that... I have lost my motivation.
Wish you trust me more!
Then will you study by yourself?
Sure!
OK, you can study as you please.
I'll go out to play!
Nobita!!!
Why don't you understand?
Nobita, we are believing in you!
You have to grow mature.
This is your fault..
Farewell!
Nobita!
Reflect on your thoughts!
If you did homework everyday, it'd never have ended up like this1
I don't remember raising you to be like this!
You're not my son!
Please reflect yourself!
I'm hungry!  should've ran from home after eating!
Wish I could stay somewhere else....
That's it! I'll visit Shizuka-chan's house.
She's going to be my wife in the future after all...
But maybe I'm a bit too early?
Shizuka!
Sorry, thanks for waiting.
Oh my. Wait, Shizuka!
It's fine now.
Thanks!
Do you like your dress?
Young Master Suneo!
I can see that you're absorbed in your project, but the lunch is gonna be cold.
I can't take my hands off, have to finish it before evening.
Then mother will feed you ..
Then,  open your mouth!
Tasty!
Good boy! Have bites!
Gouda General Store
You must be kidding me, mum! It's raining!
You must do your job!
Please gimme pocket money!
You must go!
Yuo're too strict on me!
Stay put, I'll tie your raincoat.
Okay...
Then I go !
Be careful on the road!
I have nowhere to stay....
I have reached the riverside.
Nobi-chan! Nobi-chan!
Doraemon!
You're speaking in Mum's voice.
Don't you want to come home?
Never! Not at all!
Don't be so stubborn!
Why don't you reflect upon yourslef?
Mind your own business!
Why'd my parents want me back home when they don't even love me?
But I think your parents really love you.
I should've not been born only.
Hey, you're going too far, y'know!
Today is my birthday, the day which disappointed them.
See you soon!
Wanna see?
What really happened on the day you were born?
No, it'll only increase sadness.
What if your parents were happy on your birthday?
What will you do if they were not happy?
Snail Shell-House!
I give you this shell, that you can forever call as your home.
Let's go! I'm coming with you
Did we scolded him a little too much?
I'll see what he's doing now...
Nobita, Nobita!
Earlier in time, this used to be my dad's room.
The desk is too new.
Nobita-kun!
What?
I'll take care of your luggage.
Since you wouldn't be needing them!
I wonder...
Ah, someone's on the door.
A thief?
It can't be!
Who is it?
Where is my baby?
Where's my baby?
Stop hiding and come out!
Huh, where's my baby?
Excuse us, but what are you looking for?
Oh, Dad's very young and handsome.
Who are you?
How could you forget the face of your own child?
Nobita-kun, you're not born yet. Remember?
Child?
That's it! I'd forgotten!
I came back running from work
after I received the call.
Excuse us, but you probably need to visit the hospital.
Right!
Hold on!
Bamboo 'copter!
"The battery is dead"
Anywhere Door!
"Failure"
Special Tracking Tri-Cycle!
We are not babies anymore to ride on Tri-Cycle like this!
Never-mind that!
How are we going to make it at this speed?
Don't worry, just press that button!
That boy is older than me and but still riding on a Tri-Cycle for babies!
Press the button on the middle!
They're gone!
Now, press the button on the right!
What is this?
It takes the scent of dad and catches up to him!
It runs the Shortest distance in ten times the speed.
Ten times the speed!
Go!
Too fast!
Great, right?
Like this, can we really catch up with the dad?
Hope so.
Hope it works out somehow!
Nobita-kun, we're on a train track! Faster, faster!
We're gonna die!
Oh no!
We're finally back on a good ol' road.
Where is dad?
Dad's running!
This is the hospital where I was born. Let's go!
Oh, wait!
Mr. Nobi! Mr. Nobi!
Yes?
Congratulations, your wife has given birth to a baby boy!
Yes! Thanks for your hard work!
This way please!
Yes, well...
Ah, I'm so excited to see my son!
Me too!
I wonder how he looks...
I'm probably looking like the present me.
He's got a big round face, just like his mother
Daddy, it's me!
The baby's there, dear.
Yes, i see.
How cute!
Let us have a look!
He has wrinkles all over his face, and he looks like a monkey.
How dare you say that!
I missed a heartbeat!
Newly born children will have the same looks
What's the deal with those children?
They're always following me.
I don't know what their parents have taught them
Speaking of which, where's my mother?
She said she'll go back home.
It Should be and you just missed
She was happy?
But of course!
They are talking about Grandma!
Tamako-chan!
Yes?
Well, thank you for marrying me!
Don't mention it!
Ah, yes, then I forgive you!
It's feeding time
Ah? Breast-feeding?
Ah, no father, as a matter of ~ ~
I said
Say, what should we name our son?
I've thought up of a decent name already.
Nobi Nobita, don't you like the name?
Nobita, Nobi Nobita!
Wish they'd name me better!
They should ask me!
Don't do that! You'll be scolded again!
But...
The meaning of the name? Of course there are !
Oh dear! How beautiful!
Every time you come to the hospital
You will be looking at this tree
Like this long branch of a tree extending smoothly...
growing to the higher heights in a majestic way...
It is really incredible
I think , I can imagine it ..
Nobita!
Nobi Nobita!
I hope he'll be a good boy.
Of course he's an excellent kid.
He'll be excellent in everything.
He'll be good at sports if he's like you.
Dad just summarized all your weak points...
Will he be a scholar or a politician...
Nobita-kun...
It'd have been nice if he became an artist.
Anything is good, as long as as he be useful to society..
I'm Nobi Nobita, but...
However, I can't become like you...
Are you going to encourage me? That's very kind of you...
The tree is...!
No... !
That's it! This tree was re-located.
Nobita-kun!
What are you doing?
Like a long branch of a tree Extending smoothly, growing to the higher heights...
I hope he'll be a good boy.
Of course, he will!
Gimme my bag!
Here you go!
What about those books?
Yeah, not necessary anymore...
Also, seems I was wrong
Yes!
Let's go home!
Yep!
Go!
Where?
Where that tree is!
I hope that the tree's safe...
Nobita!
I knew it!
You have grown up really!
But the books are gone...
Never mind! I'm happy!
If Dad and Mum saw this, they Will definitely understand!
Maybe...
Nobita!
Dad, Mom!
Daddy!
Are you hurt?
Are you OK? No injuries?
OK, I'm fine.
We were dead worried about you!
Where were you?
Sorry, I...
Don't worry. It's our fault that we went too far...
Daddy!
That tree...
That's....
That tree was felled there.
Yes, but...
Oh, the sound of these leaves really takes me back!
The Day Nobita was born...
It feels just like that tree, how wonderful!
A long branch of a tree Extending smoothly, growing to the higher heights...
Nobita, Nobi Nobita! This is the origin of your name!
Are you glad that I was born?
Of course, We are happy!
Rain has stopped.
It's really beautiful!
I think we can see much farther if we could go up to the tree.
Elevator Button!
Doraemon!
I still remember that day when I first met you
Being enveloped in the soft wind
You were there for me
I have been wanting to see you
from a very long time
Memories of that moment is not by chance
I want to see you, my white angel
with the shining face
The End